我们从矢量乘标量开始。
We begin with multiplication of a vector by a scalar.
当你乘向量a时
When you multiply a vector a
通过标量，这个乘法因子只是重新缩放向量的大小或长度。
by a scalar, this multiplicative factor just re scales the magnitude or the length of the vector.
让我们看向量两次
Let us look at the vector two times a
这与向量a的方向相同，但长度是向量a的两倍。
this is in the same direction as the vector a but is twice as long.
这是向量b
This is vector b
矢量由其大小和方向来定义。所以这个向量b在空间的任何地方都是一样的，包括在原点。
a vector is defined by its magnitude and direction. So this vector b is the same anywhere in space, including at the origin.
如果我要负点乘以5，这个向量是b的反方向，是长度的一半。
If I want minus point five times be, this vector is in the opposite direction of b and is half the length.
现在让我们看看向量加法。
Now let's look at vector addition.
这里是向量a，这里是b，我们如何用图形方式添加它们？
Here's a vector a here is b how do we add them graphically?
我们把b的尾巴滑到a的头上
We slide the tail of b to the head of a
它们的和是从a的尾部到b的头部的向量
and their sum is the vector drawn from the tail of a to the head of b
我也可以把a的尾部滑动到b的头部来增加a到b
I could have also added a to b by sliding the tail of a to the head of b
你可以看到这是一个平行四边形，一些向量c
you can see that this makes a parallelogram, and the some vector c
只是这个平行四边形的对角线。
is just the diagonal of this parallelogram.
是 啊。
Yeah.
减法可以看作是乘法和加法。
Subtraction can be thought of as just multiplication and addition.
如果c等于a减去b
If I have c is equal to a minus b
我只需要把a加到向量减去b
I just need to add a to the vector minus b
负b是负的1乘以b
minus b is negative one times b
这就是向量。
which is this vector here.
现在我只需要把a加到-b
Now I only have to add a to minus b
再举一个例子
let's do another example
在这里。我的向量a和b不是从原点开始的。但是由于矢量在空间的任何地方都是一样的，我可以在这里进行这个过程。
here. My vectors a and b do not start at the origin. But since vectors are the same anywhere in space, I can go through the process here.
我要a减b
I want a minus b
所以我先乘以我的负1，得到负b
so I first multiply be my minus one to find minus b
然后我移动了负β的尾部
and then I moved the tail of minus beta, the head of a
把这两个加起来。
and add the two like this.